<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fragment on </title>
    <link>http://w20-framework.github.io/tags/fragment/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fragment on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="http://w20-framework.github.io/tags/fragment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Web framework</title>
      <link>http://w20-framework.github.io/docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://w20-framework.github.io/docs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;W20 is a web solution designed to allow developers to quickly and simply create enterprise-grade &lt;strong&gt;Single Page
Application&lt;/strong&gt; (SPA). It is &lt;strong&gt;server agnostic&lt;/strong&gt; which means it can work with any HTTP capable server technology. In fact,
it can even work without any server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;benefits&#34;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;W20 provides a &lt;strong&gt;modular programming model for web applications&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing entire parts of web frontend to be reused
across applications. These parts are called fragments and can be published on any HTTP server as static resources.
Creating a frontend application with W20 becomes as easy as choosing the fragments you want to load and how you want
them to be configured from a single configuration file.
In fact, W20 itself is distributed as several fragments which are, aside from its core, all optional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;organization-of-an-application&#34;&gt;Organization of an application&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A W20 application is a Single Page Application (SPA) composed of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;master page&lt;/strong&gt; (usually &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt;, but can be dynamically generated). It is the entry point of the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;configuration file&lt;/strong&gt; (usually &lt;code&gt;w20.app.json&lt;/code&gt;, but can be dynamically generated).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One or more &lt;strong&gt;fragment(s)&lt;/strong&gt;. A fragment is a bundle of web resources described by a JSON manifest which must be
accessible by HTTP from the browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    (docroot)
        |-index.html
        |-w20.app.json
        |-fragments
            |-fragment1
                |-fragment1.w20.json
                ...
            |-fragment2
                |-fragment2.w20.json
                ...
            ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-master-page&#34;&gt;The master page&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A single page application is a web application that fits on a single web page called the master page (usually
&lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt;). Assuming you keep your static resources in a &lt;code&gt;bower_components&lt;/code&gt; directory, a sample code of a
minimalist master page in W20 would be :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!doctype html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html data-w20-app&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Application title&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; 
            data-main=&amp;quot;bower_components/w20/modules/w20&amp;quot; 
            src=&amp;quot;bower_components/requirejs/require.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;div data-ng-view&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things worth noticing :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;data-w20-app&lt;/code&gt; attribute on the &lt;code&gt;html&lt;/code&gt; tag that will load the configuration of your W20 application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag, where we reference &lt;a href=&#34;http://requirejs.org/&#34;&gt;RequireJS&lt;/a&gt; and instruct it to load W20.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A W20 application is also an &lt;a href=&#34;http://angularjs.org&#34;&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt; application. Therefore you should add a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag
with the &lt;code&gt;data-ng-view&lt;/code&gt; attribute. This will include rendered templates into the master page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-configuration-file&#34;&gt;The configuration file&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The configuration file &lt;code&gt;w20.app.json&lt;/code&gt; is where you set-up your application. As mentioned earlier, a W20 application is
basically composed of a set of fragments (a fragment is a bundle of web resources). All are optional except one : the
core fragment of W20, thus it has to be referenced in the &lt;code&gt;w20.app.json&lt;/code&gt;. This is done by specifying the path to its
configuration file (&lt;em&gt;a.k.a&lt;/em&gt; the fragment manifest) :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;bower_components/w20/w20-core.w20.json&amp;quot;: {}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fragments&#34;&gt;The fragments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important concept in W20 is the &lt;strong&gt;fragment&lt;/strong&gt;. A W20 application is composed of one or more fragment(s). A fragment is
a bundle of web resources (templates, css, javascript, &amp;hellip;). Each one is intended to serve a purpose and &lt;strong&gt;can be reused
across applications&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, W20 provides an optional fragment with native AngularJS implementations of UI
components such as &lt;em&gt;datagrid&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;combo boxes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fragment-manifest&#34;&gt;Fragment manifest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reference web resources and how they are to be configured, each fragment has its own manifest file located at the
root of the fragment. The only mandatory property is the fragment unique identifier :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &amp;quot;id&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;fragment-identifier&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By convention, the manifest file is called after the fragment identifier and suffixed by &lt;code&gt;.w20.json&lt;/code&gt;. In this example,
the fragment manifest would be &lt;code&gt;fragment-identifier.w20.json&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fragment-modules&#34;&gt;Fragment modules&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now suppose we want to use the fragment discussed above but only the &lt;em&gt;datagrid&lt;/em&gt; component. For that, W20 offers a finer
granularity to configure your application. Within a single fragment, there can be several units called &lt;strong&gt;modules&lt;/strong&gt; which
are loaded only if you decide to reference them in your application configuration. That way, you can load a fragment
without being forced to load all of its resources.
The sample code below shows how to declare a fragment module :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &amp;quot;id&amp;quot; : &amp;quot;fragment-identifier&amp;quot;,

    &amp;quot;modules&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;module1&amp;quot;: {
            &amp;quot;path&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;{fragment-identifier}/modules/module1&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;autoload&amp;quot; : true|false,
            &amp;quot;configSchema&amp;quot;: {
                ...
            }
        }
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things worth noticing :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;{fragment-identifier}&lt;/code&gt; is used by W20 as a placeholder to target the fragment path. This ensures paths are always
relative to the fragment manifest location. It is particularly useful if the fragment is intended to be used across
applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;path&lt;/code&gt; attribute is mandatory for RequireJS to load the module when it is required by the application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fragments modules are &lt;a href=&#34;http://requirejs.org/docs/whyamd.html#amd&#34;&gt;AMD compliant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a configuration JSON schema is provided for a specific module in the fragment manifest, the configuration specified
here will be validated against it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-it-works&#34;&gt;How it works&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The master page is the one and only entry point of your web application. By adding the following &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag in it,
two things happen :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RequireJS is loaded&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once RequireJS is loaded, it loads &lt;code&gt;bower_components/w20/modules/w20.js&lt;/code&gt; (notice there is no extension in the
&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; when pointing to the &lt;code&gt;w20.js&lt;/code&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; 
            data-main=&amp;quot;bower_components/w20/modules/w20&amp;quot; 
            src=&amp;quot;bower_components/requirejs/require.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;w20.js&lt;/code&gt; is the core implementation of W20. Once loaded, it will automatically parse your application configuration
file &lt;code&gt;w20.app.json&lt;/code&gt; to :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;detect which fragments to load&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;detect which modules to load for each fragment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;validate configuration for each fragment and module (&lt;code&gt;w20.app.json&lt;/code&gt;) against its schema
(&lt;code&gt;fragment-identifier.w20.json&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;load AMD modules using RequireJS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;load the home view from the application module of the W20 core fragment into the master page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;pull-right margin-top-20&#39;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#39;manual&#39; class=&#34;btn btn-u&#34;&gt;Next: start reading the manual...&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;clearfix&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web framework basics</title>
      <link>http://w20-framework.github.io/docs/manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://w20-framework.github.io/docs/manual/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;W20 is an integration framework for the AngularJS-based Single Page Applications (SPA). It offers a modular programming
model based on fragments and high-level services to accelerate your Web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;fragments-and-configuration&#34;&gt;Fragments and configuration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;W20 and its applications are organized around the idea of &lt;strong&gt;fragments&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-fragment&#34;&gt;What is a fragment ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A W20 application is made of several fragments that brings different concerns to the application.
A fragment is a collection of web resources (JavaScript &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asynchronous_module_definition&#34;&gt;AMD modules&lt;/a&gt;, stylesheets, HTML templates&amp;hellip;)
that often but not necessarily depends on each other. The dependency between modules inside a fragment is orchestrated by the use of
the &lt;a href=&#34;http://requirejs.org/&#34;&gt;RequireJS&lt;/a&gt; library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of a fragment as a coherent set of resources linked together for the purpose of &lt;strong&gt;organization&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;reusability&lt;/strong&gt;.
By including and configuring a fragment you can bring the corresponding aspect and/or asset to your web application without having to worry about
the intrinsic details of the fragment itself. Inside a fragment, the module dependency system guarantees that the dependencies of a module will be loaded before the module
itself. This is especially important for large applications that often require an important number of JavaScript modules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments-vs-modules&#34;&gt;Fragments vs modules&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we talk about a module, we refer to a JavaScript AMD module, as used in the RequireJS library. That is, to say thing shortly, a .js file
whose content is wrapped in a &lt;code&gt;define&lt;/code&gt; call (AMD modules are explained in greater detail further down). A fragment on the other hand is a collection of modules.
It is described by a manifest which exposes configuration properties. When you include and configure a fragment in your application you can generally choose
which modules to activate inside of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragment-manifest&#34;&gt;Fragment manifest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each fragment contains a JSON manifest that serves as a descriptor for the fragment configuration possibilities. The fragment manifest has two main goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To expose the available modules of the fragment and their available configuration options. It is important to understand that the fragment manifest does
not configure the fragment. It exposes what configuration will be possible according to a configuration schema. In the next section we will see how to
actually configure the fragment when you declare it inside your application manifest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To allow the declaration of additional RequireJS configuration. On application start, each RequireJS configuration of each fragments, if present, are merged
together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The properties of a fragment manifest are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt;: a mandatory string with no space which identifies the fragment. No fragment with the same id can be included at the same time in an application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;name&lt;/code&gt;: an optional name for the fragment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;description&lt;/code&gt;: an optional description of the fragment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;requireConfig&lt;/code&gt;: an optional object with the properties of a RequireJS configuration object. In the example below we add a simple RequireJS configuration
for module mapping (this allow to &amp;laquo;map&amp;raquo; a module to a name, which can be used for creating aliases or for module substitution). For an exhaustive list and
description of the RequireJS configuration options, please have a look  at its &lt;a href=&#34;http://requirejs.org/docs/api.html&#34;&gt;API&lt;/a&gt;.
Remember that this configuration will be merged with all the other declared fragment configuration on application start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;demo-fragment&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;requireConfig&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;map&amp;quot;: {
           &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;: {
             &amp;quot;mappedModule&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;path/to/module/to/map&amp;quot;
        }
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;modules&lt;/code&gt;: an optional object whose keys are the name of the exposed modules of the fragment. The value of those keys is an object with
the module path and the configuration schema. The configuration schema contains the name of the configuration properties available for the module.
In the example below we expose a module &amp;laquo;demoModule&amp;raquo; inside a fragment with id &amp;laquo;demo-fragment&amp;raquo; and a configuration property named &amp;laquo;demoConfig&amp;raquo;
of type string for the module demoModule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;demo-fragment&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;modules&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;demoModule&amp;quot;: {
             &amp;quot;path&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;{demo-fragment}/modules/demoModule&amp;quot;,
             &amp;quot;autoload&amp;quot; : true,
             &amp;quot;configSchema&amp;quot;: {
                 &amp;quot;title&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Demo module configuration&amp;quot;,
                 &amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;object&amp;quot;,
                 &amp;quot;additionalProperties&amp;quot;: false,
                 &amp;quot;properties&amp;quot;: {
                     &amp;quot;demoConfig&amp;quot;: {
                         &amp;quot;description&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;A description of the demoConfig property&amp;quot;,
                         &amp;quot;type&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;string&amp;quot;
                     }
                 }
             }
        }
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a few additional things to note in this last example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the &lt;code&gt;path&lt;/code&gt; property we used the fragment id enclosed in curly braces (&lt;code&gt;{demo-fragment}&lt;/code&gt;). This alias is automatically registered based
on the fragment id and points to the location of the fragment manifest (it is a RequireJS mapping). You can (and should for reusability consideration)
use this alias in all other fragments
and in the application to refer to the fragment location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;autoload&lt;/code&gt; attribute specify if the module should be loaded automatically or only if required by another module. By &amp;laquo;required by another module&amp;raquo;, we refer
to the AMD definition and the dependency management between modules as used in RequireJS (through the use of a &lt;code&gt;define&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;require&lt;/code&gt; call). If not specified, the
module will not be autoloaded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;type&lt;/code&gt; property of the &amp;laquo;demoConfig&amp;raquo; option has been specified as a string. This means that when the property will be given its value in the application
manifest, passing a type other than a string will raise an error. The other type available are object, array, boolean and number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;additionalProperties&lt;/code&gt; property of the configuration schema specify if additional properties can be given when configuring this module in the application
manifest. In this example, trying to configure any other property than a &amp;laquo;demoConfig&amp;raquo; one for this module in the application manifest will raise an error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;callout callout-info&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;display:table; width: 100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; width: 50px; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            
            
                &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle icon-2x&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 30px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
            
            
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The configuration schema is optional. You can simply declare the module along with its path and eventually ask for it to be autoloaded (false if not specified). This
is often the case when you simply want to include a module that has no particular configuration in your business fragment.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;W20 is packaged and distributed as multiple fragments. Your application will then be composed of those fragments and your own business fragments.
Now that we have a better understanding of the notion of fragment, we can proceed to the configuration step in which we actually include and configure those fragments
in our application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;configuration&#34;&gt;Configuration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application configuration happens in an application manifest. This manifest must be named &lt;strong&gt;w20.app.json&lt;/strong&gt; because, in the absence of
a remote manifest, the framework will fall back to looking for a JSON file with this name at the application root.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The role of the application manifest is to reference fragments through their manifest URL and configure them specifically for the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fragment-declaration&#34;&gt;Fragment declaration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To include a fragment in your application, specify the path of the fragment manifest as a key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &amp;quot;bower_components/w20/w20-core.w20.json&amp;quot;: {}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;w20-core&lt;/code&gt; fragment will be loaded with all its modules whose &lt;code&gt;autoload&lt;/code&gt; property is set to true. An alias &lt;code&gt;{w20-core}&lt;/code&gt; is now
pointing to &lt;code&gt;bower_components/w20&lt;/code&gt;, the location of the fragment manifest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;callout callout-info&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;display:table; width: 100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; width: 50px; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            
            
                &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle icon-2x&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 30px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
            
            
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;bower_components&lt;/code&gt; is the default name of the folder in which &lt;a href=&#34;http://bower.io/&#34;&gt;Bower&lt;/a&gt; installs the web dependencies. Bower is one of the most popular
package manager for web application. It should be installed to ease application development and/or use the w20 application generator. W20 fragments are available
in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://bower.io/search/?q=w20&#34;&gt;Bower registry&lt;/a&gt; and will be installed to the bower_components folder if you choose this way of installation.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fragment-configuration&#34;&gt;Fragment configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declaring a fragment like above can sometimes be enough. Autoloaded modules will be available and that may be sufficient.
However, most of the time, you will configure the fragment&amp;rsquo;s modules according to your need or because an explicit configuration value is required.
To configure the modules of the fragment add a &lt;code&gt;modules&lt;/code&gt; section:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &amp;quot;bower_components/w20/w20-core.w20.json&amp;quot; : {
        &amp;quot;modules&amp;quot;: {
            &amp;quot;application&amp;quot;: {
                &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;my-app&amp;quot;
            }
        }
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the above configuration, the &lt;code&gt;application&lt;/code&gt; module of &lt;code&gt;w20-core&lt;/code&gt; will be configured with the corresponding object (defining
the unique identifier of the application in this case). This module is normally defined as automatically loaded so this
definition will only serve to configure it. To load a module that is not automatically loaded without configuration, just
specify it with an empty object:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &amp;quot;bower_components/w20/w20-core.w20.json&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;modules&amp;quot;: {
            &amp;quot;application&amp;quot;: {
                &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;my-app&amp;quot;
            }
        }
    },

    &amp;quot;bower_components/other-fragment/other-fragment.w20.json&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;modules&amp;quot;: {
            &amp;quot;my-module&amp;quot;: {}
        }
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example above &amp;laquo;my-module&amp;raquo; will be loaded without any configuration. If it was not declared and the module was not set to be autoloaded, &amp;laquo;my-module&amp;raquo;
would not be loaded on application start even if it belongs to the &amp;laquo;other-fragment&amp;raquo; fragment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;callout callout-info&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;display:table; width: 100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; width: 50px; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            
            
                &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle icon-2x&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 30px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
            
            
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;If a configuration JSON schema is provided for a specific module in the fragment manifest, the configuration specified
here will be validated against it. Also, if a default configuration is provided for a specific module in the fragment manifest, the configuration specified here
will be merged with it, overriding it. If no default configuration is provided, the configuration is provided as-is to the module.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/fragments.png&#34; alt=&#34;fragments-overview&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;masterpage&#34;&gt;Masterpage&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;W20 uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://angularjs.org/&#34;&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt; as a core framework for application development.
Thus, its applications are &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single-page_application&#34;&gt;Single Page Application (SPA)&lt;/a&gt;.
Only one HTML page is served with an outermost html doctype and a root tag &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. This page is called the &lt;strong&gt;masterpage&lt;/strong&gt;.
The masterpage serves two roles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instruct the browser to load the RequireJS library with the w20 loader as the main module. The w20 loader is a module of the core fragment and
referenced in the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; attribute of the script which loads RequireJS and who will take care of bootstrapping the application. A &lt;code&gt;w20-app&lt;/code&gt; attribute is mandatory on the root
element of the masterpage. Application loading is explained in further details
in the following section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Declare the unique &lt;code&gt;ng-view&lt;/code&gt; element of the application which will include view templates. View change is handled through client-side
routing which associates an URL to a template. This template is rendered in the &lt;code&gt;ng-view&lt;/code&gt; tag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!doctype html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;!-- Sample masterpage for a W20 app --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;html data-w20-app&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Application title&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; 
            data-main=&amp;quot;bower_components/w20/modules/w20&amp;quot; 
            src=&amp;quot;bower_components/requirejs/require.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;div data-ng-view&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;callout callout-info&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;display:table; width: 100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; width: 50px; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            
            
                &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle icon-2x&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 30px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
            
            
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;You can notice that HTML attributes that are not part of the HTML specification (such as &lt;code&gt;w20-app&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;ng-view&lt;/code&gt;) are prefixed with
&amp;laquo;data-&amp;raquo;. This allow to keep templates valid against HTML validator by defining those attributes as &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Global_attributes/data-*&#34;&gt;custom attributes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;callout callout-warning&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;display:table; width: 100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; width: 50px; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            
            
            
                &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-exclamation-triangle icon-2x&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
            
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Note that the w20 module is referenced without the .js extension. It is a common mistake to include the .js extension while referring to module but this
is not accepted by RequireJS. The module file name is &amp;laquo;w20.js&amp;raquo; but it must be referenced by &amp;laquo;w20&amp;raquo; only.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional configuration can be provided:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;w20-app&lt;/code&gt; attribute can be provided with the URL of the application manifest as the value:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;html data-w20-app=&amp;quot;/resources/configuration&amp;quot;&amp;gt; ... &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that case, a request is made for retrieving the remote configuration. Without any value provided, the w20 loader will look
for a &lt;code&gt;w20.app.json&lt;/code&gt; at the same level as the masterpage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;w20-app-version&lt;/code&gt; attribute, when provided a value, will append this value as an extra query string to URLs of resources.
This is useful for cache busting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;html data-w20-app data-w20-app-version=&amp;quot;1.0.0&amp;quot;&amp;gt; ... &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;w20-timeout&lt;/code&gt; attribute specify the number of seconds to wait before giving up on loading a script.
Setting it to 0 disables the timeout. The default if not specified is 7 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;html data-w20-app data-w20-timeout=&amp;quot;3&amp;quot;&amp;gt; ... &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;w20-cors-with-credentials&lt;/code&gt; attribute accept a boolean that specify if whether or not cross-site Access-Control requests should be made using credentials
such as cookies or authorization headers. By default the value is false.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;html data-w20-app data-w20-cors-with-credentials=&amp;quot;true&amp;quot;&amp;gt; ... &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;core-fragment&#34;&gt;Core fragment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core fragment of W20 is the most important fragment of the framework and the only one that is mandatory.
It provides the fundamental aspect of the framework, mainly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asynchronous_module_definition&#34;&gt;AMD&lt;/a&gt; infrastructure through &lt;a href=&#34;http://requirejs.org/&#34;&gt;RequireJS&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An MVC runtime through &lt;a href=&#34;https://angularjs.org/&#34;&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application loading and initialization through the &lt;code&gt;w20&lt;/code&gt; module referenced in the masterpage,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A permission model which enables to reflect backend security,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensive culture support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for HATEOAS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No CSS framework is provided in the core fragment to let you free of this choice. However, you can simply add
an appropriate fragment of W20 to bring frameworks such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbootstrap.com/&#34;&gt;Twitter Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; (w20-bootstrap-3)
or &lt;a href=&#34;https://material.angularjs.org/latest/&#34;&gt;Angular Material&lt;/a&gt; (w20-material). For additional information,
please consult the &lt;a href=&#34;http://w20-framework.github.io/docs/manual/ui/&#34;&gt;UI&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of this manual will focus mainly on the core fragment. Additional fragments documentation can be found in the corresponding
section of the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core fragment provides the &lt;code&gt;w20&lt;/code&gt; module which is responsible for application initialization. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at how a W20 application load
itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;application-loading&#34;&gt;Application loading&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once RequireJS is loaded, the &lt;code&gt;w20&lt;/code&gt; module becomes the entry point of a W20 application as the main module.
Think of it as a &amp;laquo;fragment loader&amp;raquo;. Its initialization sequence is as follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loading and parsing of the application configuration (&lt;code&gt;w20.app.json&lt;/code&gt; or remote configuration).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loading and parsing of all the declared fragment manifests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computing of a global RequireJS configuration along with the list of all modules to load.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loading of all modules needed at startup time at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initialization of each loaded modules through their lifecycle callbacks (pre -&amp;gt; run -&amp;gt; post).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last phase should be a little bit unclear at this point because we did not introduce modules lifecycle yet.
We included it here to give you the full initialization sequence for future reference. Modules are documented in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://w20-framework.github.io/img/w20-loading.png&#34; alt=&#34;w20loading&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;modules&#34;&gt;Modules&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;amd&#34;&gt;AMD&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript logic in W20 are defined in AMD modules. An AMD module is defined using the global function &lt;code&gt;define&lt;/code&gt; exposed by RequireJS.
AMD module can be named but it is strongly recommended that you use anonymous AMD modules, each one living in its own JavaScript file.
They have the following form:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;define([
        // (1) list of the dependencies of this module
], function(/* (2) list of injected dependencies (in the same order as (1)) */) {
    
    // (3) module factory function body (private scope of the module)

    return {
        // (4) public signature of the module that can be injected 
        // when requested as a dependency of another module
    };
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us expand a little bit on each part of this module definition:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(1) The list of dependencies is composed of path to dependencies of this module, which are often themselves AMD modules.
The path can be an absolute path or a map key if a RequireJS mapping has been defined. Remember that fragments manifest location are
automatically aliased by their fragment id enclosed in curly braces. This means that you can reference a W20 fragment or your own one as
a dependency like this:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;define([
&#39;{w20-core}/modules/application&#39;, 
&#39;{your-fragment}/modules/your-module&#39;
], ... );
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that modules are referenced without their .js extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;callout callout-info&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;display:table; width: 100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; width: 50px; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            
            
                &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle icon-2x&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 30px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
            
            
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Third party libraries location are also aliased. For instance AngularJS distribution location is aliased by &lt;code&gt;{angular}&lt;/code&gt;.
This means that you can reference a dependency to angular.js with &lt;code&gt;{angular}/angular&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(2) The last parameter to the &lt;code&gt;define&lt;/code&gt; function is the factory function. Its parameters are the public value returned by the dependencies defined in (1) in
the same order. That is, if we take the example above, the public value of the &amp;laquo;application&amp;raquo; module as first argument and the public value of &amp;laquo;your-module&amp;raquo; as
second argument.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(3) The body of the factory function constitute the private part of the module. This part is not available to other modules.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(4) The return value of a module is the public part it exposes to the world. The value of this return will be what will be injected
in other modules factory function if that module is a dependency of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;define([
&#39;{w20-core}/modules/application&#39;,
&#39;{yourFragment}/modules/yourModule&#39;
], function (applicationPublic, yourModulePublic) {
 
 var privateValue = &#39;I am a private string&#39;;
 
 return {
    publicValue: &#39;I am a public string&#39;
 }

});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if we suppose the module above to be named &amp;laquo;demo.js&amp;raquo; inside a fragment with id &amp;laquo;example&amp;raquo;, if this module is defined as a dependency of another,
the last one can access the publicValue property of the object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;define([
    &#39;{example}/modules/demo&#39;,
], function (demo) {

    console.info(demo.publicValue); // &amp;quot;I am a public string&amp;quot;

});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;module-configuration&#34;&gt;Module configuration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To access the configuration of a module it needs to depend on the &lt;code&gt;module&lt;/code&gt; module. This special module is used to retrieve the module id, its location
and the value of its configuration options (those declared in the application manifest).
If we suppose a module &amp;laquo;sample&amp;raquo; with the following configuration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;some-fragment/path/some-fragment.w20.json&amp;quot;: {
    &amp;quot;modules&amp;quot;: {
        &amp;quot;sample&amp;quot;: {
            &amp;quot;prop&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Value of property one&amp;quot;
        }
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The configuration is retrieved inside the &amp;laquo;sample&amp;raquo; module like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;define([
    &#39;module&#39;,
], function (module) {

    var config = module &amp;amp;&amp;amp; module.config() || {};
    
    console.log(config.prop); // &amp;quot;Value of property&amp;quot;
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The statement &lt;code&gt;module &amp;amp;&amp;amp; module.config() || {}&lt;/code&gt; is the idiomatic way of safely retrieving the module configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lifecycle-callbacks&#34;&gt;Lifecycle callbacks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &amp;laquo;Application loading&amp;raquo; section we have seen that the initialization sequence ended with each loaded modules going
through their &amp;laquo;lifecycle callbacks&amp;raquo;. Actually this is only the case for modules that declares lifecycle callbacks. If a module does
not declare any lifecycle callback then it is simply loaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lifecycle callbacks happens when all fragments have been collected and the RequireJS
configuration has been merged. There are 3 lifecycle callbacks which runs in the order: &lt;code&gt;pre&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;run&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;post&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of them are optional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is guaranteed that every modules will run their &lt;code&gt;pre&lt;/code&gt; callback before any other modules run their &lt;code&gt;run&lt;/code&gt; callback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is guaranteed that every modules will run their &lt;code&gt;run&lt;/code&gt; callback before any other modules run their &lt;code&gt;post&lt;/code&gt; callback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A module dependency will have its callback called before the module requiring it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To integrate a module into the lifecycle management of the application, you must add the following code to the public
signature of the module (i.e the return value of the factory function):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;return {
    ...

    lifecycle: {
        pre: function (modules, fragments, callback) {},
        run: function (modules, fragments, callback) {},
        post: function (modules, fragments, callback) {}
    }

    ...
};
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can omit the unsupported callbacks (for instance, just leaving the &lt;code&gt;pre&lt;/code&gt; one). If the loader recognize one or more
lifecycle callbacks, they will be invoked during W20 initialization with the following arguments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;modules&lt;/code&gt; is an array of all public modules definitions,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fragments&lt;/code&gt; an array of all loaded fragment manifests,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;callback&lt;/code&gt; is a function that &lt;strong&gt;MUST&lt;/strong&gt; be called to notify the loader that any processing in this phase is done for
this module (including asynchronous processing). If a module do not call its callback, the whole initialization process
is blocked for a specified amount of time. After that, it is cancelled and a timeout error message is displayed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lifecycle callbacks are useful hooks for application initialization. The &lt;code&gt;pre&lt;/code&gt; callback for instance will run before AngularJS
initialization, the subject of the next section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;angularjs-initialization&#34;&gt;AngularJS initialization&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before AngularJS initialization, it is guaranteed that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All AMD modules needed at startup are loaded,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their factory functions have been run in the correct order,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their &lt;code&gt;pre&lt;/code&gt; lifecycle callbacks have been run and all modules have notified the loader that they have finished loading
their asynchronous resources if any.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AngularJS initialization is done explicitly with the &lt;code&gt;angular.bootstrap()&lt;/code&gt; function on the document element. It occurs
in the &lt;code&gt;run&lt;/code&gt; lifecycle callback of the &lt;code&gt;application&lt;/code&gt; module. From this moment AngularJS initialize normally; you can read more
about the initialization process &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.angularjs.org/guide/bootstrap&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;angularjs-modules&#34;&gt;AngularJS modules&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;amd-vs-angularjs-modules&#34;&gt;AMD vs AngularJS modules&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.angularjs.org/guide/module&#34;&gt;AngularJS modules&lt;/a&gt; are not to be confused with AMD modules. We said at the
begining of this guide that when we refer to a &amp;laquo;module&amp;raquo;, it is an AMD module. We will continue to do so and use the term &amp;laquo;AngularJS module&amp;raquo;
to refer to the notion of module in AngularJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the AMD point of view, AngularJS modules have no meaning. However, AngularJS modules are fundamental for
structuring an application correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-an-angularjs-module&#34;&gt;What is an AngularJS module ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AngularJS modules allow to register services, factories, controllers, directives, providers and other concepts
such as configuration or run block. AngularJS modules are also fundamental for unit testing. Each AngularJS module can only be loaded once per injector.
Usually an AngularJS app has only one injector and AngularJS modules are only loaded once. Each test has its own injector and AngularJS modules are loaded multiple times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;angularjs-module-dependencies&#34;&gt;AngularJS module dependencies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait a minute. Did we not already talk about dependencies between modules ? Yes, we did. We talked of dependencies between AMD modules.
But AngularJs modules can also list other AngularJS modules as their dependencies. Depending on an AngularJS module implies that the required AngularJS module
needs to be loaded before the requiring AngularJS module is loaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// firstModule.js
define([&#39;{angular}/angular&#39;], function (angular) {
  var firstAngularModule = angular.module(&#39;first&#39;, []);
});

// secondModule.js
define([&#39;{angular}/angular&#39;, &#39;firstModule&#39;], function(angular) {
  var secondAngularModule = angular.module(&#39;second&#39;, [&#39;first&#39;]);
});

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example above the dependency between AngularJS modules is declared as an array in the second argument to the &lt;code&gt;angular.module&lt;/code&gt; function. AngularJS maintains an injector
with a list of names and corresponding objects. An entry is added to the injector when a component is created and the object is returned whenever it is referenced using the registered name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does that fit with the dependency system between AMD modules ?  It is important to remember that the purpose of AMD modules and AngularJS modules is totally different.
The dependency injection system built into AngularJS deals with the objects needed in a component while dependency management in RequireJS deals with JavaScript files. In other word,
if an AngularJS modules depends on another AngularJS modules, this means that they must be loaded in the correct order. The &lt;code&gt;secondModule&lt;/code&gt; depend on the &lt;code&gt;firstModule&lt;/code&gt; to be loaded first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;angularjs-modules-and-w20&#34;&gt;AngularJS modules and W20&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To correctly initialize AngularJS, the &lt;code&gt;application&lt;/code&gt; module must know all the top-level declared
AngularJS modules. To expose them properly, you must add the following code to the public signature of modules that
declare AngularJS modules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;return {
    ...

    angularModules: [ &#39;angularModule1&#39;, &#39;angularModule2&#39;, ... ]

    ...
};
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All &lt;code&gt;angularModules&lt;/code&gt; arrays of AMD public signature modules are concatenated and the resulting array is passed to
the &lt;code&gt;angular.bootstrap()&lt;/code&gt; function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;callout callout-info&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;display:table; width: 100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; width: 50px; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            
            
                &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-info-circle icon-2x&#34; style=&#34;line-height: 30px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
            
            
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;display:table-cell; vertical-align: middle;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Note that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to add the transitive AngularJS modules.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>